import type { QuestionList } from '~/types'

export const hiragana: QuestionList = {
  name: 'hiragana',
  title: '平仮名',
  data: [
    {
      question: 'あ',
      answer: 'a',
      explantion: 'あ',
    },
    {
      question: 'い',
      answer: 'i',
      explantion: 'い',
    },
    {
      question: 'う',
      answer: 'u',
      explantion: 'う',
    },
    {
      question: 'え',
      answer: 'e',
      explantion: 'え',
    },
    {
      question: 'お',
      answer: 'o',
      explantion: 'お',
    },
    {
      question: 'か',
      answer: 'ka',
      explantion: 'か',
    },
    {
      question: 'き',
      answer: 'ki',
      explantion: 'き',
    },
    {
      question: 'く',
      answer: 'ku',
      explantion: 'く',
    },
    {
      question: 'け',
      answer: 'ke',
      explantion: 'け',
    },
    {
      question: 'こ',
      answer: 'ko',
      explantion: 'こ',
    },
    {
      question: 'さ',
      answer: 'sa',
      explantion: 'さ',
    },
    {
      question: 'し',
      answer: 'shi',
      explantion: 'し',
    },
    {
      question: 'す',
      answer: 'su',
      explantion: 'す',
    },
    {
      question: 'せ',
      answer: 'se',
      explantion: 'せ',
    },
    {
      question: 'そ',
      answer: 'so',
      explantion: 'そ',
    },
    {
      question: 'た',
      answer: 'ta',
      explantion: 'た',
    },
    {
      question: 'ち',
      answer: 'chi',
      explantion: 'ち',
    },
    {
      question: 'つ',
      answer: 'tsu',
      explantion: 'つ',
    },
    {
      question: 'て',
      answer: 'te',
      explantion: 'て',
    },
    {
      question: 'と',
      answer: 'to',
      explantion: 'と',
    },
    {
      question: 'な',
      answer: 'na',
      explantion: 'な',
    },
    {
      question: 'に',
      answer: 'ni',
      explantion: 'に',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぬ',
      answer: 'nu',
      explantion: 'ぬ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ね',
      answer: 'ne',
      explantion: 'ね',
    },
    {
      question: 'の',
      answer: 'no',
      explantion: 'の',
    },
    {
      question: 'は',
      answer: 'ha',
      explantion: 'は',
    },
    {
      question: 'ひ',
      answer: 'hi',
      explantion: 'ひ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ふ',
      answer: 'fu',
      explantion: 'ふ',
    },
    {
      question: 'へ',
      answer: 'he',
      explantion: 'へ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ほ',
      answer: 'ho',
      explantion: 'ほ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ま',
      answer: 'ma',
      explantion: 'ま',
    },
    {
      question: 'み',
      answer: 'mi',
      explantion: 'み',
    },
    {
      question: 'む',
      answer: 'mu',
      explantion: 'む',
    },
    {
      question: 'め',
      answer: 'me',
      explantion: 'め',
    },
    {
      question: 'も',
      answer: 'mo',
      explantion: 'も',
    },
    {
      question: 'や',
      answer: 'ya',
      explantion: 'や',
    },
    {
      question: 'ゆ',
      answer: 'yu',
      explantion: 'ゆ',
    },
    {
      question: 'よ',
      answer: 'yo',
      explantion: 'よ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ら',
      answer: 'ra',
      explantion: 'ら',
    },
    {
      question: 'り',
      answer: 'ri',
      explantion: 'り',
    },
    {
      question: 'る',
      answer: 'ru',
      explantion: 'る',
    },
    {
      question: 'れ',
      answer: 're',
      explantion: 'れ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ろ',
      answer: 'ro',
      explantion: 'ろ',
    },
    {
      question: 'わ',
      answer: 'wa',
      explantion: 'わ',
    },
    {
      question: 'を',
      answer: 'wo',
      explantion: 'を',
    },
    {
      question: 'ん',
      answer: 'n',
      explantion: 'ん',
    },
  ],
}

export const katakana: QuestionList = {
  name: 'katakana',
  title: '片仮名',
  data: [
    {
      question: 'ア',
      answer: 'a',
      explantion: 'ア',
    },
    {
      question: 'イ',
      answer: 'i',
      explantion: 'イ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ウ',
      answer: 'u',
      explantion: 'ウ',
    },
    {
      question: 'エ',
      answer: 'e',
      explantion: 'エ',
    },
    {
      question: 'オ',
      answer: 'o',
      explantion: 'オ',
    },
    {
      question: 'カ',
      answer: 'ka',
      explantion: 'カ',
    },
    {
      question: 'キ',
      answer: 'ki',
      explantion: 'キ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ク',
      answer: 'ku',
      explantion: 'ク',
    },
    {
      question: 'ケ',
      answer: 'ke',
      explantion: 'ケ',
    },
    {
      question: 'コ',
      answer: 'ko',
      explantion: 'コ',
    },
    {
      question: 'サ',
      answer: 'sa',
      explantion: 'サ',
    },
    {
      question: 'シ',
      answer: 'shi',
      explantion: 'シ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ス',
      answer: 'su',
      explantion: 'ス',
    },
    {
      question: 'セ',
      answer: 'se',
      explantion: 'セ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ソ',
      answer: 'so',
      explantion: 'ソ',
    },
    {
      question: 'タ',
      answer: 'ta',
      explantion: 'タ',
    },
    {
      question: 'チ',
      answer: 'chi',
      explantion: 'チ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ツ',
      answer: 'tsu',
      explantion: 'ツ',
    },
    {
      question: 'テ',
      answer: 'te',
      explantion: 'テ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ト',
      answer: 'to',
      explantion: 'ト',
    },
    {
      question: 'ナ',
      answer: 'na',
      explantion: 'ナ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ニ',
      answer: 'ni',
      explantion: 'ニ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヌ',
      answer: 'nu',
      explantion: 'ヌ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ネ',
      answer: 'ne',
      explantion: 'ネ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ノ',
      answer: 'no',
      explantion: 'ノ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ハ',
      answer: 'ha',
      explantion: 'ハ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヒ',
      answer: 'hi',
      explantion: 'ヒ',
    },
    {
      question: 'フ',
      answer: 'fu',
      explantion: 'フ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヘ',
      answer: 'he',
      explantion: 'ヘ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ホ',
      answer: 'ho',
      explantion: 'ホ',
    },
    {
      question: 'マ',
      answer: 'ma',
      explantion: 'マ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ミ',
      answer: 'mi',
      explantion: 'ミ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ム',
      answer: 'mu',
      explantion: 'ム',
    },
    {
      question: 'メ',
      answer: 'me',
      explantion: 'メ',
    },
    {
      question: 'モ',
      answer: 'mo',
      explantion: 'モ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヤ',
      answer: 'ya',
      explantion: 'ヤ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ユ',
      answer: 'yu',
      explantion: 'ユ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヨ',
      answer: 'yo',
      explantion: 'ヨ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ラ',
      answer: 'ra',
      explantion: 'ラ',
    },
    {
      question: 'リ',
      answer: 'ri',
      explantion: 'リ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ル',
      answer: 'ru',
      explantion: 'ル',
    },
    {
      question: 'レ',
      answer: 're',
      explantion: 'レ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ロ',
      answer: 'ro',
      explantion: 'ロ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ワ',
      answer: 'wa',
      explantion: 'ワ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ヲ',
      answer: 'wo',
      explantion: 'ヲ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ン',
      answer: 'n',
      explantion: 'ン',
    },
  ],
}

export const youon: QuestionList = {

  name: 'youon',
  title: '拗音',
  data: [
    {
      question: 'きゃ',
      answer: 'kya',
      explantion: 'きゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'きゅ',
      answer: 'kyu',
      explantion: 'きゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'きょ',
      answer: 'kyo',
      explantion: 'きょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'しゃ',
      answer: 'sha',
      explantion: 'しゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'しゅ',
      answer: 'shu',
      explantion: 'しゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'しょ',
      answer: 'sho',
      explantion: 'しょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ちゃ',
      answer: 'cha',
      explantion: 'ちゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ちゅ',
      answer: 'chu',
      explantion: 'ちゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ちょ',
      answer: 'cho',
      explantion: 'ちょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'にゃ',
      answer: 'nya',
      explantion: 'にゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'にゅ',
      answer: 'nyu',
      explantion: 'にゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'にょ',
      answer: 'nyo',
      explantion: 'にょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ひゃ',
      answer: 'hya',
      explantion: 'ひゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ひゅ',
      answer: 'hyu',
      explantion: 'ひゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ひょ',
      answer: 'hyo',
      explantion: 'ひょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'みゃ',
      answer: 'mya',
      explantion: 'みゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'みゅ',
      answer: 'myu',
      explantion: 'みゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'みょ',
      answer: 'myo',
      explantion: 'みょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'りゃ',
      answer: 'rya',
      explantion: 'りゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'りゅ',
      answer: 'ryu',
      explantion: 'りゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'りょ',
      answer: 'ryo',
      explantion: 'りょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぎゃ',
      answer: 'gya',
      explantion: 'ぎゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぎゅ',
      answer: 'gyu',
      explantion: 'ぎゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぎょ',
      answer: 'gyo',
      explantion: 'ぎょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'じゃ',
      answer: 'ja',
      explantion: 'じゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'じゅ',
      answer: 'ju',
      explantion: 'じゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'じょ',
      answer: 'jo',
      explantion: 'じょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'びゃ',
      answer: 'bya',
      explantion: 'びゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'びゅ',
      answer: 'byu',
      explantion: 'びゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'びょ',
      answer: 'byo',
      explantion: 'びょ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぴゃ',
      answer: 'pya',
      explantion: 'ぴゃ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぴゅ',
      answer: 'pyu',
      explantion: 'ぴゅ',
    },
    {
      question: 'ぴょ',
      answer: 'pyo',
      explantion: 'ぴょ',
    },

  ],
}

export default {
  hiragana,
  katakana,
  youon,
}
